American Psychological Association Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Administration, 1918-1985 (Box 29-292)
  - Departmental Offices File, 1948-1984 (Box 132-290)
    - Educational Affairs Office (Box 132)
      - Projects and programs (Box 151)
        - Projects
          - Human Behavior Curriculum Project
            - Administrative file
              - Steering Committee
                - General, 1974-1977, undated
                - Meetings, 1972-1974, undated
              - Stevens Point material, Stevens Point, Wisc., 1974-1975, undated (Box 166)
              - "S" miscellaneous, 1972-1977, undated, (2 folders)
              - Trautwein, Marvin, 1974-1976
              - "T" miscellaneous, 1972-1976, undated
              - "U" miscellaneous, 1975-1977, undated
              - "V" miscellaneous, 1974-1976 (Box 167)
              - Wartburg College, Waverly, Iowa, 1976
              - Watson House, Carleton College, Northfield, Minn., 1975, undated
              - Wertheimer, Michael, 1972-1975, undated
              - "W" miscellaneous, 1972-1977, undated, (2 folders)
              - "X-Z" miscellaneous, 1973-1975
            - Modules
              - Arends
                - Correspondence
                - 1974-1976
                - 1977, undated (Box 168)
                - Proposal, 1975
                - Student booklet, drafts, 1976-1977
                - Teacher handbook, drafts, 1976
              - Guy
                - Correspondence
                - Apr. 1974-June 1976
                - July 1976-Aug. 1977, undated
                - Miscellaneous chapters and background material, 1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 169)
                - Student booklet
                - Drafts and revisions, 1976-1977, undated
                - General, 1976, undated
                - Teacher handbook (Box 170)
                - Drafts and revisions, 1977, undated
                - General, 1976-1977
              - Hillman
                - Correspondence, 1974-1977
                - Student booklet (Box 171)
                - Drafts and background material 1976, undated
                - Original, 1977
                - Teacher handbook
                - Drafts and background material, 1976
                - Original, 1977
              - Iwamoto, 1975-1977
              - Kasschau (Box 172)
                - Correspondence, 1974-1977, (2 folders)
                - Student booklet
                - Drafts and revisions, 1976-1977, undated
                - Master copy, 1976-1977
                - Teacher handbook (Box 173)
                - Background material, 1965-1975, undated
                - Drafts and revisions, 1976, n.d, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 174)
                - Master copy, 1976, (3 folders)
              - Legrand
                - Correspondence, 1975-1977
                - Student booklet, draft, 1976 (Box 175)
              - Marsh
                - Correspondence, 1974-1977, (2 folders)
                - Miscellaneous chapters and background material, 1974-1977, undated, (1 folder) (Box 176)
                - Student booklet
                - Drafts and revisions, 1975-1977, undated
                - General, 1976, undated
                - Teacher handbook
                - Drafts and revisions, 1975-1977, (1 folder) (Box 177)
                - General, 1976
              - Mendelson
                - Correspondence, 1974-1977, (2 folders)
                - Miscellaneous chapters and background material, undated (Box 178)
                - Student booklet, 1976-1977, undated
                - Teacher handbook
                - Drafts and revisions, undated
                - General, 1976-1977, undated
              - Phillips (Box 179)
                - Correspondence
                - 1974-1977, (2 folders)
                - National trials
                - Miscellaneous revisions 1975-1976, undated, (2 folders)
                - Student exam questions, undated (Box 180)
                - Student booklet
                - Drafts and revisions, 1974-1976, undated, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 181)
                - General, 1976
                - Student manual, final drafts, 1977
                - Teacher handbook
                - Drafts and revisions, 1976, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 182)
                - Final draft, 1977, undated
              - Saxon, 1975-1978, undated (Box 183)
              - Teaching aides, undated
      - Surveys
        - Internship agency evaluation, 1967-1968, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Checklist
            - Drafts and correspondence, 1976-1980
            - Questionnaires and correspondence, 1976-1977
          - Chronicle chart, degrees offered, 1978-1979, undated (Box 184)
          - Inservice training guidelines, 1980
          - State textbooks and adoption, 1977
          - Teacher training, 1972-1977, undated
          - Textbook preference and evaluation, 1977-1978
          - Undergraduate psychology programs, 1973
        - Undergraduate courses with international aspects (Box 185)
          - Background and reference material, 1980-1983, undated, (2 folders)
          - Record of interviews and leads, undated
          - Rejected material, 1982-1983
          - Syllabi
            - A-C, 1982-1983, undated
            - D-Z, 1980-1983, undated, (3 folders) (Box 186)
    - Human Resources Office (Box 187)
      - Manpower
        - Correspondence
        - Clearinghouse for Information on Psychology's Manpower, 1975
        - General, 1967-1980, (3 folders)
        - Manpower analysis and planning (Box 188)
          - Correspondence, 1956-1969
          - Graphs, charts, and tables
            - APA supplementary questionnaire, 1966
            - Characteristics of psychologists from the
              - National Science Foundation's National
              - Register of Scientific and Technical
              - Personnel, 1960-1961
            - National Register of Scientific and Technical Personnel
              - 1966
              - 1968
                - Material for American Psychological Association article, 1968
            - National register tables, 1968
            - National Science Foundation register samples, 1962
            - Various, 1962-1963, undated (Box 189)
          - Minutes and related material, 1965-1969
        - Miscellany, 1966-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 190)
        - Questionnaires
          - Doctoral tallies, 1966
          - Exotech Systems, Inc., 1973
          - National Register of Scientific and Technical
            - Personnel, 1967-1970, undated
          - National Science Foundation
            - Data elements, undated
            - Register, 1954-1970 (Box 191)
            - Report, 1968
        - Reference data
          - Budget, 1969-1970, undated
          - Control numbers, 1972-1977, undated
          - Data analyses, 1964-1973
          - Database, 1975-1976
          - Employment status, 1974
          - Format, master file, 1975
          - Initial tabulations, 1974-1975
          - Major boards and committees, 1964, undated
          - Membership statistics, 1976
          - Memberships, 1977, undated
          - Miscellany, 1968-1976, undated (Box 192)
          - National Register of Scientific and Technical Personnel, 1966
          - Placement operation, 1964-1966
          - Salary, 1964-1968, undated
          - State officers study, 1964, undated
        - Reports
          - Background
            - Mental health, 1967-1971
            - National coalition, 1975-1976, undated
            - Psycho-socio consanguinity, 1960-1972, undated (Box 193)
            - Various, 1970-1973, undated
            - Williamsburg Conference, Williamsburg, Va., 1972, undated
          - Organization
            - Annual, 1962-1964
              - Aug. 1973, (2 folders)
              - Computer study, 1976 (Box 194)
              - Computer use
                - 30 Jan. 1976
                - 16 June 1976
              - Master file, 1973
              - National Research Council, meeting of professionals, 1967-1969, undated
              - Staff study, 1971-1973, undated
              - Systems aspects, 1967-1970, undated
              - Various, 1965-1978, n.d (Box 195)
        - Subject file
          - Advisory committee, 1977
          - American Geological Institute, 1969, undated
          - American Institute of Physics, 1967-1973, undated
          - American Psychiatric Association, 1963-1969, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 196)
          - Analysis and Planning Society, 1969-1973, undated
          - Bachelor's degrees in psychology, 1969-1972
          - Computer study, 1970-1976, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 197)
          - Convention placement, 1956-1966, undated
          - Five-year plan, 1972, undated
          - Manpower information, requests for, 1968-1970, undated
          - Meier, Richard, undated
          - Minority Fellowship Grant, 1972-1975, undated (Box 198)
          - National Institute of Mental Health
            - Conference on patterns and levels of training, 1969-1972
            - Doctoral education grant, 1963-1975, undated, (2 folders)
            - Manpower data systems, 1971, undated, (1 folder) (Box 199)
          - Professional associations, 1969, undated
          - Proposal for a manpower system, 1967, undated
          - Proposal system, 1972
          - Undergraduate grant, 1973
          - Use of manpower data, undated
          - Woodrow Wilson Foundation dissertation fellows, 1972
        - Surveys
          - Degree recipients
            - Correspondence, 1969
            - Reference material, 1969, undated, (2 folders)
            - Reports and drafts, 1968-1970, undated
            - Unusable responses, 1969 (Box 200)
          - Development, 1974, undated
          - Division 2: Teaching of Psychology, 1969, (3 folders)
          - Graduate applicant study
            - Correspondence, 1969
            - Reference data, 1965-1967, undated
          - Manpower, 1976 (Box 201)
          - Master's degree respondents, 1969
          - Membership standards, 1973
          - Mental health, 1970
          - National Institute of Mental Health, funding cuts, 1973
          - Placement, 1975
          - Psychology bachelor of arts degrees, 1968-1970
          - Psychology teaching, 1966-1967
          - Response chart, 1974
          - Statistical Package for the Social Studies, 1977, undated
    - Professional Affairs Office
      - General correspondence
        - Centor, Arthur, and Joan S. Zaro, 1974-1979
          - A-C, (3 folders)
          - D-K, (7 folders) (Box 202)
          - L-R, (6 folders) (Box 203)
          - Sa-Sl
          - Sm-Sz (Box 204)
          - T-Z, (3 folders)
        - Chronological file (by specialist)
          - Arnold, Pam, 1980
          - Batchelor, Walter F., 1976-1977
          - Centor, Arthur
            - Jan. 1974
            - Feb. 1974-Mar. 1977, (11 folders) (Box 205)
            - Apr. 1977-May 1978, (3 folders) (Box 206)
          - Golann, Stuart E. 1967-1969, (3 folders)
          - Kilburg, Richard, 1978
          - Logan, Mary D., 1977-1979, (2 folders)
          - Margolin, Joseph B.
            - Sept.-Dec. 1962
            - Jan. 1963-Sept. 1964, (11 folders) (Box 207)
            - Oct.-Dec. 1964 (Box 208)
          - McMillan, John H.
            - Jan. 1965-Mar. 1969, (8 folders)
            - Apr. 1969-Dec. 1971, (7 folders) (Box 209)
          - Parkman, Frances, 1978-1979
          - Simon, Gottlieb C., 1971-1974, (6 folders) (Box 210)
      - Interdepartmental memoranda
        - Board of Directors, 1974-1979
        - Board of Professional Affairs, 1975-1979
        - Committees, 1974-1979, (2 folders) (Box 211)
        - Task forces, 1974-1979
      - Related offices file
        - State and Professional Affairs Office
          - Docter, Richard F., 1965-1966
          - Golann, Stuart E., and John H. McMillan, 1967
          - McMillan, John H.
            - Apr. 1964-June 1965
            - Aug. 1965-Dec. 1967, (4 folders) (Box 212)
        - State Association Office, 1975-1978
          - Buklad, William
            - A-J, (4 folders)
            - K-Z, (5 folders) (Box 213)
        - State Legislation Office
          - Nemir, Ralph W.
            - Mar. 1973-Dec. 1974, (3 folders)
            - Jan.-Nov. 1975, (3 folders) (Box 214)
      - Projects and programs
        - Awards programs
          - Distinguished Professional Contribution Award
            - Correspondence
              - June 1972-Aug. 1977, (2 folders)
              - Sept. 1977-July 1979, (2 folders) (Box 215)
            - Miscellaneous material, 1975-1979
            - Nominees, 1975-1979
          - Distinguished Professional Contribution to Applied Psychology, nominees, 1979
          - Distinguished Professional Contribution to Knowledge, nominations, 1979 (Box 216)
          - Distinguished Professional Contribution to Public Service, nominations, 1979
        - Conference on the Professional Preparation of Clinical Psychologists
          - General Correspondence, 1958-1965, (4 folders)
          - Correspondence
            - Advisory Committee, 1964
            - Plenary sessions, 1965
            - Preconference, 1963-1965, undated (Box 217)
            - Proceedings, 1964-1966
            - Process notes, 1965
          - Reports, statements and summaries
            - A-H, 1948-1965, undated, (4 folders)
            - J-S, 1962-1965, undated, (6 folders) (Box 218)
            - T-Z, 1963-1965, undated (Box 219)
            - Miscellaneous reports, 1962-1964, undated, (2 folders)
            - Statements from psychology department heads, 1964-1965
            - Summaries of material, 1964
            - Summaries of sessions, 1963, undated
            - Working papers and plenary sessions (Box 220)
              - Reports, 1965, undated
              - Summaries, 1965, undated
          - Subject file
            - Agenda and related items, 1963-1969, undated, (3 folders)
            - Background material
              - 1963-1964
              - 1965, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 221)
            - Conference agenda and related material, 1964
            - Conference proceedings, first draft, 1965-1966
            - Conference report, correspondence regarding, 1965-1966, undated
              - District of Columbia psychologists, 1964
              - Issues
                - General, 1964, undated
                - Professional training statement
                - First draft and reactions, 1965
                - Second draft and reactions, 1965 (Box 222)
              - Miscellany, 1962-1965, undated, (2 folders)
              - Preconference material, 1965, undated
              - Proceedings, pages 1-213, 1965, (2 folders)
              - Process notes, 1965
                - Work groups 1-3
                - Work groups 4-8, (2 folders) (Box 223)
        - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals, agenda and miscellany, 1973-1983
          - Correspondence
            - 1973-1979, (2 folders)
            - 1980-1983, (2 folders) (Box 224)
          - Reports and related material, 1973-1981, (2 folders)
        - Task Force on Descriptive Behavior Classification (Box 225)
          - Background, 1975-1979
          - Correspondence and related material, 1966-1979, (2 folders)
          - Reports, 1975-1979, (2 folders)
        - Task Force on Descriptive Classification of Children's Behavior, 1979-1984, (3 folders) (Box 226)
        - Task Force on Environment and Behavior, 1975-1976
        - Task Force on Model Criteria, 1974-1976
        - Task Force on Psychological Testing of Minority Groups, 1967
        - Task Force on Sex Bias and Sex Role Stereotyping (Box 227)
          - Bibliography, proposal, and background, 1975
          - Correspondence, 1974-1976, 1982-1983, (2 folders)
          - Final reports and summary, 1974-1975
          - Minutes, 1982
          - Miscellaneous material, undated
          - Questionnaire (Box 228)
            - 1974, (5 folders)
            - 1976, (4 folders) (Box 229)
          - Reports, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 230)
        - Task Force on Specialty Criteria
          - Agendas, 28-29 Apr. 1970
          - Correspondence, 1978-1979
          - Reports and notes, 1979
          - Survey results
            - A-G, 1979
            - H-Z, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 231)
      - Subject file
        - Aging, 1961-1966, 1981
        - American Association of State Psychology Boards, 1965-1967
        - American Board of Examiners in Professional Psychology, reports, bulletins and bylaws, 1948-1966
        - Annual Conference Advisory Committee, correspondence, reports, proposals and miscellaneous material, 1964
        - Annual convention, 1977, 1983-1984 (Box 232)
        - Archives, file listing, 1969-1972
        - Boulder Conference, Boulder, Colo., 1948-1950
        - Budget, federal, 1980-1982, (2 folders)
        - Chronic Mental Patient Conference, 1977-1978
        - Commitment, 1977-1978
        - Community mental health centers, 1966
        - Current procedural terminology, 1977
        - Education for the handicapped, 1977, 1982
        - Ethnic minority affairs, 1975-1979 (Box 233)
        - Fee Panel, survey and results analysis, 1968
        - Graduate Medical Education National Advisory Committee, 1978-1983, (2 folders)
        - Health carrier reimbursement, 1978-1979
        - Health planning, 1978-1980
        - Insurance for APA members, 1960-1962
        - Legal issues, 1979-1981 (Box 234)
        - Licensing, 1978
        - Malpractice, 1963-1965
        - Mental health legislation
          - Conference, 1964-1965, (3 folders)
          - Correspondence, 1966-1977 (Box 235)
          - Related material, 1963
        - Military psychologists, 1979-1982
        - Miscellaneous material, 1977-1981, (3 folders)
        - Practice of medicine, surgery and psychology, Tennessee laws, 1953-1958 (Box 236)
        - Professional Standards Review Organization, 1978-1981
        - Psychological Research and Rehabilitation, 1959-1963, (2 folders)
        - Senior citizen legislation, testimony
          - American Dental Association to Council on Social Work Education, 1967
          - National Association of Social Workers to State of Oregon, 1967
        - Standards for providers of psychological services, 1973-1976 (Box 237)
        - Standing board and committee nominations
          - Nominations
            - Correspondence, 1958-1978, (3 folders)
            - General
              - 1965-1966
              - 1976-1977, (4 folders) (Box 238)
              - 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 239)
            - Related material, 1977-1978, undated
        - State psychological associations, Board of Professional Affairs conferences, 1980-1984
        - Sunset legislation, 1979-1980
          - Folder 1
          - Folder 2 (Box 240)
        - Third Conference on Research in Psychotherapy, 1964-1967
        - Virginia Academy of Science, 1963-1964, undated
    - Programs and Planning Office
      - Correspondence
        - Chronological file
          - Mar. 1965-Dec. 1971, (4 folders)
          - Jan. 1972-Dec. 1973, (4 folders) (Box 241)
          - Jan. 1974-Dec. 1976, (6 folders) (Box 242)
          - Jan. 1977-Apr. 1978, (6 folders) (Box 243)
          - May-Nov. 1978, (7 folders) (Box 244)
          - Dec. 1978-Apr. 1979, (5 folders) (Box 245)
          - May-Aug. 1979, (4 folders) (Box 246)
          - Sept. 1979-Sept. 1980, (5 folders) (Box 247)
          - Oct.-Dec. 1980 (Box 248)
        - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978, undated
      - Projects and programs
        - Congressional Fellowship Office
          - Correspondence, 1964-1977
          - Curriculum vitae, 1974-1977
          - Miscellany, 1975-1982
          - Reports, 1976-1978
    - PsycINFO
      - Correspondence, 1973-1983
      - Meetings, agenda and related material
        - 25-26 Sep. 1981
        - 19 Feb. 1982 (Box 249)
        - 24 June 1982
        - 24-25 Sep. 1982
        - 21 Oct. 1982
      - Minutes, 1969-1982
      - Miscellany
        - 1969-1980
        - 1981, undated (Box 250)
      - Reports, origin and development, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
    - Public Information Office
      - Administrative officer
        - Forest L. Vance
          - Correspondence
            - 1963
            - 1964-1965, (2 folders) (Box 251)
    - Scientific Affairs Office
      - Correspondence
        - Early career awards, 1972-1976, (3 folders)
        - General, 1968-1981, (4 folders) (Box 252)
        - Members, 1977-1978
        - Scientific Awards Committee, 1974, 1976 (Box 253)
      - Miscellany, 1960-1980, undated, (5 folders)
      - Projects and programs (Box 254)
        - Task Force on Environment and Behavior
          - Annual reports, 1973-1976, undated
          - Correspondence
            - Aug. 1972-Dec. 1976, (5 folders)
            - Jan.-Nov. 1977, undated (Box 255)
          - Newsletter
            - General, 1971-1977, undated, (4 folders)
            - Issues, 1974-1976, undated (Box 256)
          - Resource book
            - Chapter 1: Overview of the Field of Environment and Behavior, 1976, undated
            - Chapter 2: Graduate Programs in Environment and Behavior, 1975-1977, undated, (2 folders)
            - Chapter 3: Curricula Models, 1976, undated
            - Chapter 4: Review of Textbooks and Reference Material, 1976, undated (Box 257)
            - Chapter 5: Careers in Environment and Behavior, 1974-1976, undated
            - Chapter 6: Federal and Private Funding, undated
            - Chapter 7: Journals and Newsletters in Environment and Behavior, 1975-1977, undated
            - Chapter 8: Man and the Biosphere, 1974-1975, undated
            - Chapter 9: Organizations as a Resource, and Chapter 10: Personal Interest Inventory, 1976-1977, undated
            - Correspondence, 1975-1977, undated
          - Subject file (Box 258)
            - Air pollution, 1970-1971, undated
            - American Institute of Architects, 1974, undated
            - Artificial barriers, 1976, undated
            - Attitudes and values, 1973-1975, undated
            - Behavioral ecology, 1974
            - Bibliographies, 1971-1974, undated
            - Conferences, 1970-1974
            - Consortium
              - Correspondence
                - 1974-1975, (2 folders)
                - 1976-1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 259)
              - Minutes, 1975-1976, undated
              - Report, 1975
            - Construction, 1971-1975, undated
            - Convention programs, 1973-1977, (2 folders)
            - Crowding, 1970-1975 (Box 260)
            - Curriculum programs, 1974-1975, undated
            - Energy, 1975-1976
            - Environment and behavior, 1972-1975, undated
            - Environmental Design Research Association
              - Final report, 1977
              - General 1974-1977, undated
            - Environmental research project, 1974
            - Environmentalists, 1970-1976, undated (Box 261)
            - Funding, 1975-1976
            - Goals and objectives, undated
            - Graduate education, 1974-1975, undated
            - Graduate programs, 1974, undated
            - Image, 1975, undated
            - Journals in environment and behavior, 1974, undated
            - Media, 1973-1975, undated
            - Miscellany, 1971-1977, undated, (2 folders)
            - National Environmental Policy Act, 1975
            - Noise pollution, 1968-1975, undated
            - Organizations, 1975-1976 (Box 262)
            - Psychological Perspectives on Environment and Behavior: Conceptual and Empirical Trends, 1974-1975, undated
            - Questionnaires, undated
            - Regional meetings, 1974-1976, undated, (2 folders)